In the last video, we talked
在上一个的视频，我们谈了(字幕翻译：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
about dimensionality reduction for
关于降维
the purpose of compressing the data.
压缩数据的目的。
In this video, I'd like
这个视频，我想
to tell you about a second application
告诉你第二个应用程序
of dimensionality reduction and that is to visualize the data.
降维，可视化的数据。
For a lot of machine learning
很多机器学习
applications, it really helps
应用程序，它真的很有帮助
us to develop effective learning
我们发展有效的学习
algorithms, if we can understand our data better.
算法，如果我们能更好地了解我们的数据。
If there is some way of visualizing
如果有一些可视化方法
the data better, and so,
数据更好，所以，
dimensionality reduction offers us,
降维提供了我们，
often, another useful tool to do so.
的时候，另一个有用的工具可以完成。
Let's start with an example.
开始吧。
Let's say we've collected a large
我们说我们已经收集了大量
data set of many statistics
数据集的统计
and facts about different countries around the world.
和事实世界不同的国家。
So, maybe the first feature, X1
所以，也许第一个特征，X1
is the country's GDP, or the
是该国的国内生产总值，或
Gross Domestic Product, and
国内生产总值，和
X2 is a per capita, meaning
X2是人均，意义
the per person GDP, X3
人均GDP，X3
human development index, life
人类发展指数，生活
expectancy, X5, X6 and so on.
期望，X5和X6，等等。
And we may have a huge data set
，我们可能有一个巨大的数据集
like this, where, you know,
这样，在那里，你知道的，
maybe 50 features for
也许50个特征
every country, and we have a huge set of countries.
每一个国家，我们有一个庞大的国家。
So is there something
所以有什么
we can do to try to understand our data better?
我们能做的更好的理解我们的数据？
I've given this huge table of numbers.
我给了这么庞大的数据表。
How do you visualize this data?
你如何表述这个数据？
If you have 50 features, it's
如果你有50个特征，它的
very difficult to plot 50-dimensional
很难绘制50维
data.
数据。
What is a good way to examine this data?
检查这个数据的一个很好的方法是什么？
Using dimensionality reduction, what
采用降维，
we can do is, instead of
我们能做的，而不是
having each country represented by
有各个国家的代表
this featured vector, xi, which
这一特征向量，而xi，
is 50-dimensional, so instead
是50维的，而不是
of, say, having a country
，说，有一个国家
like Canada, instead of
比如加拿大，而不是
having 50 numbers to represent the features
50个数字来代表的特征
of Canada, let's say we
加拿大，让我们说我们
can come up with a different feature
会有不同的特征
representation that is these
表示这些
z vectors, that is in R2.
z向量，即在R2。
If that's the case, if we
如果是这样的话，如果我们
can have just a pair of
只能有一对
numbers, z1 and z2 that
号码，Z1和Z2，
somehow, summarizes my 50
不知何故，概述了我的50个
numbers, maybe what we
数字，也许我们
can do  [xx] is to plot
可以做[ XX ]来画
these countries in R2 and
这些国家在R2和
use that to try to
利用
understand the space in
了解空间
[xx] of features of different
[ XX ]的特征关于不同的
countries [xx]  the better and
国家[ XX ]更好
so, here, what you
所以，在这里，你
can do is reduce the
可以做的是减少
data from 50
数据从50
D, from 50 dimensions
D，从50个维度
to 2D, so you can
二维的，所以你可以
plot this as a 2
画作2维
dimensional plot, and, when
图，而且，当
you do that, it turns out
你这么做，原来
that, if you look at the
如果你看看
output of the Dimensionality Reduction algorithms,
降维算法的输出，
It usually doesn't astride a
通常不在
physical meaning to these new features you want [xx] to.
物理意义的这些新特征，你需要 [XX ]。
It's often up to us to figure out you know, roughly what these features means.
往往是由我们来弄清楚你知道，大概是这些特征。
But, And if you plot those features, here is what you might find.
但是，如果情节的这些特征，这里是你可能会发现什么。
So, here, every country
所以，在这里，每一个国家
is represented by a point
是由一个点表示
ZI, which is an R2
zi，这是一个R2
and so each of those.
等每个人。
Dots, and this figure
点，这个数字
represents a country, and so,
代表一个国家，所以，
here's Z1 and here's
这里Z1和这里的
Z2, and [xx] [xx] of these.
Z2，[xx] [xx]这些。
So, you might find,
的话，你会发现，
for example, That the horizontial
为例，这个水平
axis the Z1 axis
轴Z1轴
corresponds roughly to the
大约相当于
overall country size, or
整体国家大小，或
the overall economic activity of a country.
一个国家的整体经济活动。
So the overall GDP, overall
所以整体GDP，整体
economic size of a country.
经济国家的大小。
Whereas the vertical axis in our
而在垂直轴
data might correspond to the
数据可能对应于
per person GDP.
人均GDP。
Or the per person well being,
或每人幸福，
or the per person economic activity, and,
或每个人的经济活动，并，
you might find that, given these
你可能会发现，在这些
50 features, you know, these
50个特征，你知道，这些
are really the 2 main dimensions
真的2个主要方面
of the deviation, and so, out
的偏差，因此，具
here you may have a country
在这里你可以有一个国家
like the U.S.A., which
像美国，它
is a relatively large GDP,
是一个比较大的国内生产总值，
you know, is a very
你知道，是一个非常
large GDP and a relatively
大的国内生产总值和相对
high per-person GDP as well.
高人均GDP和。
Whereas here you might have
而在这里你可能
a country like Singapore, which
新加坡这样的国家，其
actually has a very
其实有一个很
high per person GDP as well,
高人均GDP和，
but because Singapore is a much
但因为新加坡是一个多
smaller country the overall
较小国家的整体
economy size of Singapore
经济规模新加坡
is much smaller than the US.
比美国小得多。
And, over here, you would
，在这里，你会
have countries where individuals
有国家的人
are unfortunately some are less
是不幸的是有些不太
well off, maybe shorter life expectancy,
小康，也许更短的寿命，
less health care, less economic
不卫生，不经济
maturity that's why smaller
成熟，所以小
countries, whereas a point
的国家，而这一点
like this will correspond to
这样会对应
a country that has a
一个国家有一个
fair, has a substantial amount of
公平，有大量的
economic activity, but where individuals
经济活动，但那里的人
tend to be somewhat less well off.
往往有点不太好了。
So you might find that
所以你会发现
the axes Z1 and Z2
轴Z1和Z2
can help you to most succinctly
可以帮助你以最简洁的
capture really what are the
捕获真的是什么
two main dimensions of the variations
两个主要维度的变化
amongst different countries.
在不同的国家。
Such as the overall economic
如总体经济
activity of the country projected
活动的国家计划
by the size of the
的大小
country's overall economy as well
国家整体经济
as the per-person individual
以及每个个体
well-being, measured by per-person
幸福，通过人均
GDP, per-person healthcare, and things like that.
GDP，人均医疗保健，以及类似的东西。
So that's how you can
所以你可以
use dimensionality reduction, in
使用降维，
order to reduce data from
为了减少数据
50 dimensions or whatever, down
50维或什么的，下降到
to two dimensions, or maybe
二维，或者
down to three dimensions, so that
下降到三维，所以
you can plot it and understand your data better.
你可以绘制和更好地了解您的数据。
In the next video, we'll start
在接下来的视频中，我们将开始
to develop a specific algorithm,
制定具体的算法，
called PCA, or Principal Component
称为PCA，或主成分
Analysis, which will allow
分析，这将允许
us to do this and also
我们这样做也
do the earlier application I talked about of compressing the data.
使用我谈到的较早的应用来压缩数据。